One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Impasse
شجارٌ كبير
Hey! Go get more food!
هيّا، أحضروا المزيد من الطعام
We've got money now!
لدينا المال لذلك
The booze today is great!
مشروب اليوم طعمه لذيذ
No one can top the years I spent graffitiing on walls.
رسمتُ على جدران منازل الناس لسنوات طويلة
Our money...  they took it all.
...ذلك المبلغ الكبير من المال سرقوه بالكامل
Nami...
...نامي
The crew... I can't face them.
لا أستطيع مواجهة الجميع
Give 'em hell, every last one of 'em!
احرصوا على أن توسعوهم ضربًا يا رفاق
You sure 'bout that?
أمتأكد من ذلك؟
Read 'em and weep!
أرأيت؟ لقد خسرت
Now, go get the food!
هيّا، اذهب لشراء بعض الطعام
Buy up everything at the store, okay?! We've got the money!
احرص على شراء كل الطعام في المتجر، مفهوم؟ لدينا المال
Well, damn! Don't go nowhere, 'cause I'll win next time!
سُحقًا، انتظروا فحسب، سأهزمكم لاحقًا
What?! What was that?!
ماذا؟ ماذا يحدث؟
Who's there?!
ثمّة شخص ما هناك
Who the hell are you?!
من أنتم أيها الأوغاد؟
That's...
...هذا
Straw Hat Luffy!
قبعة القش لوفي
So you thought you'd come get your money back, huh? How stupid!
،إذًا فقد أتيتم لاستعادة المال صحيح أيها الأغبياء؟
You see all of us? What could the four of you possibly do?
أترون كل الرجال هنا؟ ما الّذي يستطيع أربعتكم فعله؟
But, here you are. Word is, you've got a bounty on your head.
ولكن... أنت هنا الآن ولديك مكافأة على رأسك
So why not leave your head with us?
لذلك لماذا لا تترك رأسك معنا هنا؟
He's that long-nosed wimp's captain!
إنّه قبطان طويل الأنف الضعيف ذاك
So he can't be that tough!
لا يُعقل أن يكون بتلك القوة
Bring it on, short stuff!
هيّا، أيها القصير
Gum-Gum...
...غومو غومو نو
What're you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
He's using his bare fists? Even a battleship wouldn't put a dent in that thick steel armor!
يسدّد لكمات؟ على ذلك الدرع الفولاذي الّذي حتّى مدفع سفينة بحرية لن يدمّره؟
What a joke!
يا لها من مهزلة
If you're just gonna fool around, I'll go ahead and crush you.
،إن كنت ستعبث فحسب فسأباشر بسحقك إذًا
...Cannon!
مدفع= كانون
H-He busted right through that thick armor!
أ-أَحْدَثَ حفرة في ذلك الدرع الضخم بلكمته
Hey!
مهلًا
N-Now wait a minute, guys! Let's talk things over!
تـ-تمهّلوا يا رفاق، لنتحدث أوّلًا
Let's talk...
...دعونا
Let's... Let's...
...دعو... دعو
Let's fire the cannons!
أطلقوا القذائف المدفعية
Three-Sword Style:
...أسلوب السيوف الثلاثة
Dire Raven...
...صيد
Hunt!
الغربان
Th-These cannonballs are made of iron, you know!
قـ-قذائف المدفع مصنوعة من الحديد
And the cannon?!
حتى المدفع أيضًا
Bad news! These guys are seriously bad news!
مصيبة، هؤلاء الأشخاص خطيرون بالفعل
L-Let's scram! Get out through the back door!
غا-غادروا المكان، غادروا من الباب الخلفي
You picked this fight. Don't even think about backing out.
أنتم من بدأ القتال، فلا تتصرّفوا بطريقة مثيرة للشفقة
Party Table...
...وجبة ركلة
Kick Course!
طاولة الحفلات
B-Back door's a no-go!
لا-لا يمكننا استعمال الباب الخلفي
The windows! Try the windows!
النوافذ، لنخرج عبر النوافذ
Rumble!
...رامبل
Horn Point!
نقطة تعزيز القرنين
Roseo Colonnade!
زهور كرز الأعمدة
W-W-Wait a sec, you guys!
مـ-مـ-مهلًا يا رفاق
It's the money, right?! That's what you want!
تريدون المال، صحيح؟ تريدون استعادة المال، صحيح؟
The 200 million belly that loser had, right?
المئتَي مليون  التي كان بحوزة عديم القيمة ذاك، صحيح؟
Unfortunately, that money isn't here anymore!
لسوء الحظ، لم يعد المال موجودًا هنا
Our boss, Big Bro Franky, took the money and went shopping.
أخذه زعيمنا فرانكي وذهب للتسوّق
He's working a black-market deal, so he could be anywhere by now!
وبما أنّه سيشتري شيئًا من السوق السوداء فلا ندري أين ذهب
Basically, even if you go berserk here, that 200 million belly won't come ba–
باختصار، مهما عثتم فسادًا هنا
Ahh! Zambai!
زامباي
Stop running your mouth. This was never about the money.
كفاكم من ذلك، لا علاقة للأمر بالمال
Yeah. It's too late.
نعم... فات الأوان
After we're done, not even your bones will remain.
سنوسعكم ضربًا ولن يظلّ منكم حتّى عظامكم
Not even our bones?!
حتّى عظامنا؟
You idiot! Don't let 'im scare you!
أيها الغبي لا ترتعد
"Not even your bones will remain."
"لن يظلّ منكم حتّى عظامكم"
That's our line! We're the Franky Family, professional dismantlers and bounty hunters!
،هي جملة نقولها نحن عائلة فرانكي عُمال الهدم وصائدي المكافآت
Show 'em the Franky House specialty!
أروهم اختصاص منزل فرانكي
Anything Goes Cannon!
مدفع إطلاق أيّ شيء
Here they come! Take 'em out!
ها هم قادمون، هاجموهم
S-Stand tall! Keep firing until we run out of projectiles!
لا-لا تجفلوا، واصلوا الإطلاق حتّى تنفد القذائف منّا
There're only four of 'em!
ثمّة أربعة منهم فحسب
What're those noises? Fireworks?
ما هذه الأصوات؟ ألعاب نارية؟
They're coming from the northeast... That's the Franky House!
إنّها من الشمال الشرقي، إنّها صادرة من اتجاه منزل فرانكي
Them again? What's the big fuss this time?
هم ثانيةً؟ ما سبب الجلبة الآن يا ترى؟
Yeah, it– Shh! He'll hear us!
لا أدري... صه سيسمعنا
Oh, great. They're gonna tear the place apart.
يا إلهي، إنّهم يتحمّسون كثيرًا
It sure as hell ain't no cocktail party.
إنّ لا رادع لهم بالفعل عندما يحتفلون، صحيح؟
It's okay once in a while, right? Today's a special day!
لا بأس بذلك من وقت لآخر، صحيح؟ إنّ اليوم يوم رائع
Should we go after Franky?
هل نذهب خلف فرانكي؟
Where would he be?
وأين نذهب؟
What a pain. Looks like they really don't know where the money is.
معك حق، يبدو أنّهم لا يعرفون حقًا أين المال
Even if we strangle this Franky guy, he might've already spent the money.
حتّى إن خنقنا ذلك المدعو فرانكي ...فإن كان قد أنفق المال
What now? We can wait around, but he might not be back for a while.
،ما العمل الآن؟ حتّى إن انتظرناه هنا فلن يعود إلا بعد مدة
Hey! I finished giving him first aid!
يا رفيقيّ، انتهيت من إعطائه الإسعافات الأوّليّة
I need him on a stretcher. Give me a hand!
أودّ حمله على نقّالة، لذلك ساعداني
We won't figure it out here.
البقاء هنا والحديث لن يفيدنا بأيّ شيء
Let's go back to the ship for now. Nami's all alone there.
لنعد إلى السّفينة الآن، تركنا ...نامي-سان وحدها أيضًا، لذا
There's also Robin...
...كما هنالك مسألة روبين-تشان
and the issues with the ship too.
ومشكلات السّفينة أيضًا
Yeah.
نعم
Hey, Luffy!
يا لوفي
About the ship...
...بشأن السّفينة
I've decided.
اتّخذت قراري
This is where we say goodbye to the Going Merry.
لنودّع غوينغ ميري... هنا
Galley-La Company Headquarters
شركة غاليلا المقر الرئيس
Well then, I'll be on my way.
حسنًا... سأغادر الآن
I can't believe how stubborn that guy is.
يا إلهي، يا له من رجل عنيد
We don't even know if he has it, but they keep sending me out here anyway.
رغم أنّنا نجهل إن كان يملكها أم لا
I wish they'd put themselves in my shoes.
أتمنّى أن يضعوا أنفسهم مكاني
It's Kalifa.
أنا كاليفا
Well... come in.
إذًا... ادخلي
You must be worn out, Mr. Iceburg.
لا بدّ أنّك متعب يا أيسبرغ-سان
Something to drink?
أتريد شيئًا ما لتشربه؟
Yeah.
...هذا صحيح
Today, tea would be–
لا أمانع بعض الشاي اليوم
Already brewed.
سأجهّزه
Well, that's just like you, Kalifa.
حسنٌ... هذا ما أتوقّعه منك يا كاليفا
Thank you very much.
شكرًا جزيلًا
Mr. Corgi tends to leave in a bad mood, doesn't he?
يكون السيّد كورغي غاضب دائمًا عندما يغادر، صحيح؟
What in the world does he come to ask you?
ما الّذي يأتي للحديث بشأنه يا ترى؟
Oh, that.
...نعم
He wants something I have, so he comes to persuade me to give it up.
إنّه يريد شيئًا ما بحوزتي ويقترح عليّ كلّ أنواع الصّفقات
It must be something very precious, huh?
لا بدّ أنّه شيء ثمين جدًّا، صحيح؟
Well, you see... I just tell him I don't know what he's talking about and stonewall him.
حسنًا، أخبره دائمًا أنّني لا أدري عمّ يتحدّث وأرفض طلباته
He's such a pain in the butt.
إنّهم مزعجون بالفعل
Hey! Usopp woke up!
يا رفاق، استيقظَ أوسوبّ
Really?! That's great!
فعلًا؟ هذا ممتاز
Now we can relax a little.
بإمكاننا أن نرتاح الآن
Hey, Usopp!
يا أوسوبّ
Robin isn't back yet.
...لم تعد روبين-تشان بعد
Seriously, you shouldn't worry us like that!
لا تجعلنا نقلق كثيرًا هكذا
She's right. Marching in there by yourself was reckless.
إنّها محقّة، لا أصدّق أنّك ذهبت إليهم وحدك... يا لتصرّفك المتهور
You're lucky to be alive.
أنت محظوظ لأنّك لم تمت هناك
Think before you act next time.
فكّر قليلًا قبل أن تتصرّف
Look who's talking!
انظروا من يتحدّث
I'm sorry for being such a screw-up!
آسفٌ، لأنني كنتُ عديم الفائدة
I mean it...
أنا فعلًا... أشعر بالعار يا رفاق
That money meant so much, and I let it... I let it...
كان ذلك المال ضروريًا لنا ...ومع ذلك تركته... تركته
Whoa, wait! Cool it! I-I get it already, so let go!
تمهّل لحظة، اهدأ
No really, we went through so much to get that money and I...
لكن... ذلك المبلغ الكبير الّذي كان لدينا ...بعد كلّ ما مررنا به
Usopp, you should still be in bed.
أوسوبّ، عليك أن تلزم الفراش أكثر
Hey, you need to listen to Chopper.
هيّا، استمع لتشوبّر
Then that's that.
...كما كنتُ أخشى
The money is gone for good, huh?
لن نستعيد المال، صحيح؟
Well, we won't know for sure until this Franky guy comes back.
حسنًا، لن نجزم بذلك حتّى يعود المدعوّ فرانكي
I see. I'm sorry.
فهمت... أنا آسف
But even if we don't get it back, we still have 100 million belly.
،ولكن حتّى إن لم نستعده ما زال لدينا 100 مليون بيري
So it's okay. No worries.
لذلك لا بأس، لا داعي للقلق
It's not okay! That's our money!
لكنّني لم أنسَ أمر المال
Nami...
...نامي - آسفة -
No, she's right.
لا، لا بأس
Anyway, Luffy, what about the ship? What about the Merry?
لكن يا لوفي... ماذا عن السّفينة؟ ماذا عن ميري؟
Will the remaining 100 million be enough for her repairs?
هل نستطيع إصلاحها بالمئة مليون المتبقية لدينا بطريقة ما؟
We're lucky we're at a first-class shipyard that can fix her up.
إننا محظوظون لتمكننا من إصلاحها في حوض سفانة رفيع كهذا
We'll have to refit her so she can weather the seas ahead.
فلكي تستطيع أن تشدّ الترحال في البحار، أريدها أن تصير أقوى
Usopp, about that...
...أوسوبّ، بخصوص السّفينة
We're getting a new ship.
قرّرت الحصول على سفينة جديدة
Sorry I didn't talk to you about it first,
آسف لأنّني اتّخذت القرار دون استشارتك
but I've already made up my mind.
لكنّني اتّخذت قراري بالفعل
The Going Merry took good care of us, but our journey with her ends here.
اعتنت غوينغ ميري بنا جيّدًا لكنّ رحلتنا معها تنتهي هنا
Anyway...
...وأيضًا
I took a look at the catalog Iceboss gave us.
أخذت نظرة على هذه القائمة التي أعطاها لنا العم أيس
There're loads of different ships to check out in here.
،وبينما كنت أتفقّد السّفن فيها لاحظت أنّ هنالك أنواعًا مختلفة
If we go with a used one, 100 million should get us a way bigger ship.
إن اشترينا واحدة مستعملة، سيسمح لنا المال بشراء واحدة أكبر من ميري
Hold it...
مهلًا
Just hold it, please.
مهلًا، مهلًا لحظة، لقد بالغت في هذه المزحة، هذا سخيف
I mean, look! Chopper's taking it seriously.
أرأيتم؟ حتّى تشوبّر صدّقها
Really though, someone tell our captain to cut it out already.
ما العمل مع قبطاننا هذا يا رفاق؟
Say something to him, Nami.
قولي له شيئًا ما يا نامي
So then... we really don't... have enough money to repair her?
ماذا...؟ هل يعني ذلك أنّنا لا نملك ما يكفي من المال لإصلاحها؟
It's because I let them steal the 200 million, isn't it?!
،بسبب المئتَي مليون الّتي سُرقت منّي أ-أصبحنا نفتقر للمال اللاّزم، صحيح؟
Hey, that's what's going on, right, Luffy?
أخبرني، هذا ما يحدث، صحيح يا لوفي؟
A world-class shipyard would charge premium prices, after all...
إنّ الأجر الّذي سيتقاضاه حوض سفانة ...رفيع سيكون باهظًا، لذا
No! That's not it!
كلا، ذلك ليس السبب
Then what is it?! Spit it out! Are you sugarcoating this for my sake?!
ما هو إذًا؟ أخبرني، هل تحاول مراعاة مشاعري؟
I'm not! This has nothing to do with the money getting stolen!
لستُ كذلك، لا علاقة للأمر بالمال الّذي سُرق
Then why the harebrained plan to get a new ship?!
لماذا إذًا تقول أشياء غبيّة مثل حصولنا على سفينة جديدة؟
Hey, stop it, you two!
توقّفا كلاكما
What good will bickering do? Calm down, then talk!
ما الّذي سنجنيه من القتال؟ اهدآ وتحدّثا
How can I calm down after hearing this bullshit?!
كيف لي أن أهدأ وهو يتفوّه بأمور غبيّة؟
Hey! I get that this is important, but you shouldn't get so worked up.
مهلًا، هذه مسألة هامّة لا تتحمّسا كثيرًا
She's right, Usopp. You'll get worse if you don't take it easy.
إنّها على حقّ يا أوسوبّ، عليك أن ترتاح وإلاّ لن يتحسّن جسدك
So then, I get worse!
لا أهتمّ لجسدي الآن
I can't relax when the captain casually says we'll get a new ship!
كيف سأظلّ صامتًا بينما يقول قبطاننا أنّنا سنحصل على سفينة جديدة بكلّ سهولة؟
I wasn't being casual! I decided after agonizing over it!
هذا ليس سهلًا، اتّخاذي لهذا القرار كان موجعًا لي أيضًا
And what exactly agonized you about this decision?!
كيف وعن أيّ وجع تتحدّث عنه سمح لك باتّخاذ هذا القرار؟
You've got some nerve to spout off while waving this around!
كيف تجرؤ بالحديث عن ذلك وأنت تلوّح بشيء غبيّ كهذا؟
Why'd you do that?!
لماذا فعلت ذلك؟
It was pissing me off.
لا يعجبني منظره
Tell me, Luffy, if it's not about the stolen money, then what is it about?!
يا لوفي، إن لم يكن السّبب هو المال المسروق، فما هو إذًا؟
Huh, Luffy?! Just say it already! Hey! Why won't you tell me?!
لماذا قلت ذلك يا لوفي؟ هيّا، لماذا أنت صامت؟
Don't hold back, no matter how much it stings!
إن لم تكن تراعي مشاعري فلا تُبقي أيّ شيء في داخلك
Say it! Why should I go along with this?! Huh?!
قلها، لم أقبل بالأمر ما لم أسمع سببًا وجيهًا، هيّا
The Merry can't...
...ما عادت ميري تستطيع
What was... What did you just say?
ماذا قلت توًّا؟
Don't make me repeat myself.
لا تجعلني أكرّر كلامي
The Merry... can't be repaired.
ما عاد يمكن إصلاح ميري
There's just... no way to fix her.
مهما فعلنا، فلا يمكن إصلاحها
If there were, I wouldn't be talking like this.
وإلا ما كنت لأقول أمرًا كهذا
This ship?! You mean the ship we're aboard right now?!
هذه السّفينة؟ هل تتحدّث عن هذه السّفينة الّتي نحن على متنها الآن؟
That's right. This ship won't last much longer.
هذا صحيح، سوف تغرق هذه السّفينة قريبًا
What're you saying, Luffy?
عمّ تتحدّث يا لوفي؟
It's the truth. They told us at the shipyard.
هذه الحقيقة، أخبرونا بهذا في حوض السفانة
They said she won't even reach the next island.
قالوا أنّنا لا نستطيع حتّى بلوغ الجزيرة التّالية
Is that so? She won't, huh?
فعلًا... لا تستطيع؟
You just met these guys today, and they've already convinced you to walk away?
سمحت إذًا لغرباء قابلتهم اليوم فقط بإقناعك بذلك وجعلك تستسلم هكذا؟
Say what?
ماذا قلت؟
I get that these top-notch shipwrights gave you their assessment, but...
فقط لأنّ سفانين من الطّراز ...الرّفيع أخبروك بذلك
you gave up just like that?!
استسلمت بهذه البساطة؟
We've traveled together all this time!
أبحرنا معًا طوال هذا الوقت
Past every wave! Through every battle!
تجاوزنا شتّى أنواع الأمواج والمعارك معًا
She's a precious member of this crew!
إنّها صديقتنا العزيزة
And you're just gonna abandon her in a place like this?!
هل ستتخلّى عنها في مكان كهذا؟
So that's it... Is that how little this ship means to you, Luffy?!
أهذا ما تعنيه لك هذه السّفينة يا لوفي؟
You shouldn't shout like that, Usopp.
ليس عليك الصراخ هكذا يا أوسوبّ
Please, step aside.
آسف، لكن ابتعد - ماذا؟ -
I haven't gotten through to him yet.
لم أنتهِ من حديثي معه
Usopp...
...أوسوبّ
Then can you make a more accurate assessment?!
إذًا هل تستطيع منحي معاينة دقيقة؟
We don't have our own shipwright. That's why we got those guys to check her out!
،ليس لدينا سفان على هذه السّفينة لهذا السّبب طلبنا منهم معاينتها
I get it, but asking guys like them to fix her is pointless!
لا بأس، ليس علينا أن نطلب منهم إصلاحها
I'll repair her like I always have!
سأصلحها بنفسي، كما فعلتُ دائمًا
After all, that's how we made it this far.
هكذا واصلنا الإبحار بها من الأساس
Alright! No time like the present! Give me a hand, you guys!
لنبدأ الآن، ساعدوني يا رفاق
Hey, wait, Usopp.
انتظر يا أوسوبّ
Oh, yeah, we don't have enough lumber. I'll go buy some at the shipyard.
نعم، ليس لدينا خشب كافٍ، سأذهب لشراء بعضه من حوض السفانة
Now, we've got a lot to do.
حسنًا، سيكون لدينا عمل كثير
You're not a shipwright, Usopp!
لستَ سفانًا، صحيح يا أوسوبّ؟
Hold on, Luffy!
تمهّل يا لوفي
Yeah, you're right. So what?!
نعم، هذا صحيح، وماذا في ذلك؟
I don't trust shady shipwrights who abuse their position
لكنّني لا أثق بسفانين غير مسؤولين يستسلمون بسهولة
and write things off because it's "just another ship" to them!
عن سفينة فقط لأنّها تنتمي لشخص آخر عن طريق استغلال مكانتهم حرفيينَ
Usopp...
...أوسوبّ
The lesson here...? We need to look out for the ship ourselves.
لا بدّ أن يكون هذا درسًا لإجبارنا على حماية سفينتنا بأنفسنا
I'll never give up on this ship!
أنا لن... أتخلّى عن هذه السّفينة أبدًا
Did you lose your minds?!
هل أنتم أغبياء أم ماذا؟
You all got taken in by those smooth-talking shipwrights, didn't you?!
على الأرجح أنّك خُدعت بحجّة السفانين المقنِعة، صحيح؟
The Luffy I know wouldn't have fallen for some sales pitch.
كان لوفي الّذي أعرفه ليؤمن بقوّة ميري أوّلًا
He would've been the first to believe in the Merry's strength!
بدل أن يصدّق كلام أولئك الّذين صبّ في مصلحتهم
But you didn't hesitate, acting like some wise geezer with all the answers.
إنّ إجابة واضحة كهذه تبدو مثل إجابة  يقولُها عجوز أدركَ كلّ ما في الحياة
What kind of captain makes snap decisions like that?!
كيف لك أن تتّخذ قرارًا كهذا وتتصرّف بتصرّفات القبطان فجأة؟
I was wrong about you, Luffy!
أسأت الحكم عليك يا لوفي
Wait a sec, Usopp! Luffy thought the same–
...مهلًا لحظة يا أوسوبّ، كان لوفي أيضًا
Stay out of this, Nami! This is something only I decided!
لا تتدخّلي يا نامي، هذا قرار اتّخذته أنا
And I won't budge.
لن أغيّر رأيي
No matter what you say, we're getting a new ship!
،مهما قلتَ الآن سنحصل على سفينة جديدة
We'll say goodbye to the Merry here!
وسنودّع ميري هنا
Like hell we will! I can't accept that!
لا تكن سخيفًا، لن أسمح بذلك
Listen, Luffy! Not everyone shares your carefree attitude!
اسمع يا لوفي، لا يستطيع الجميع العيش والتّطلّع للأمام مثلك
I can't just leave our wounded friend here and move on to the seas ahead!
لا أستطيع التّخلّي عن صديق مصاب هنا ومواصلة ترحالي في البحار
Don't give me that! Friend or not, humans and ships are different!
،أنت السّخيف هنا حتّى إن كانت صديقًا السّفن والنّاس مختلفون
They're the goddamn same! Merry still has some fight in her!
إنّهم سيان، ما زالت تملك ميري القوّة لتواصل العيش
But knowing you, you're probably just excited about getting a new ship.
بالنّظر لطبيعتك
You can't work this out if you're all fired up!
أنتما، هذا يكفي لا طائل من الحديث إن كنتما متأثّرين لهذه الدّرجة
Enough already!
هذا يكفي
Luffy!
لوفي
You're not the only one hurting over this!
إيّاك أن تظنّ أنّك الوحيد الّذي يشعر بالألم حيال هذا
Everyone here feels the same!
هذا هو حال الجميع هنا
If that were true, there's no way you'd get a new ship!
إن كان الأمر كذلك، من المستحيل أن تقرّر الحصول على سفينة جديدة
Fine! If you hate how I run things, you should just lea–
لا بأس، إن كنت لا تطيق قراري إلى هذا الحدّ، فغادر هذه الـ
Sanji!
...سانجي
You damn idiot. What were you about to say?!
غبيّ... ما الّذي كنتَ ستقوله؟
Cool down before you end up saying something you'll regret! Got that, Luffy?!
،هدّئ من روعك و احذر ممّا تقوله أهذا مفهوم يا لوفي؟
Sorry. I just...
...آسف، أنا فقط
That's okay, Luffy. That's probably how you really feel.
لا بأس يا لوفي، هكذا هي فعلًا حقيقة مشاعرك، صحيح؟
What'd you say?!
ماذا قلت؟
Just get rid of the useless crewmates that hold you back.
باشر بالتخلّص من أصدقائك غير المفيدين الواحد تلو الآخر وواصل تقدّمك
If you're gonna abandon the Merry...
...إن كنت ستتخلّى عن ميري
why not do the same with me?!
فلماذا لا تتخلّى عنّي أيضًا؟
Hey, Usopp. Quit talking like that.
يا أوسوبّ. لا تقل أشياء غبيّة كهذه
No, I'm serious.
كلا، أنا جاد
It's been on my mind for a while.
كنت أفكّر في هذا لفترة
To be honest, I've been thinking that I can't keep up with how monstrous you all are.
بصراحة
Like today, I couldn't even guard the money.
فاليوم... لم أستطع حتّى حراسة المال
I'll just continue to be a burden on you guys.
سأواصل التّسبّب لكم بالمتاعب فحسب
You don't need weak crew members, right?
لا تحتاج أصدقاء ضعفاء، صحيح؟
Luffy, you're the man who'll be King of the Pirates.
لوفي... أنت الرّجل الّذي سيصير ملك القراصنة
But I don't feel the need to go that far.
لكن ليس عليّ الارتقاء معك لتلك الدّرجة
Thinking back on it, I was about to sail off on my own, when you invited me to join you.
بالتّفكير في الأمر، عندما كنتُ أوشك على الإبحار، طلبتم منّي الانضمام لكم
What're you talking about? Get on already.
عمّ تتحدث؟ اركب بسرعة
You're one of us now, aren't you?
إنّنا أصدقاء الآن، أليس كذلك؟
That's all that binds us.
ذلك كلّ ما يربط بيننا
If we can't see eye to eye, then why should we travel together?!
ليس علينا الإبحار معًا عندما يكون لدينا اختلاف آراء
Hey, where're you going, Usopp?!
مهلًا، أين تذهب يا أوسوبّ؟
Where I'm going is my own business.
حيث أذهب الآن هو شأني أنا
It has nothing to do with you guys anymore.
لم يعد لديكم علاقة بذلك يا رفاق
I'm...
...أنا
leaving the crew.
سأترك الطّاقم
Why... Why aren't you saying anything?
لماذا لا تقول أيّ شيء؟
Usopp!
...أوسوبّ
Wait! This is all wrong!
انتظر لا يجب أن يكون الأمر هكذا
Hey! Turn around!
هيّا عد
Hey! Come back!
اسمع، عد إلى هنا
Don't go, Usopp!
لا تذهب يا أوسوبّ
Come back!
عد إلى هنا
Luffy...!
لوفي
Luffy! I can't follow you anymore.
لوفي، لا أستطيع مرافقتك بعد الآن
Sorry I dragged you down till the end.
آسف لتسبّبي بالمتاعب حتّى الآن
I realize that the ship belongs to you, the captain.
صحيح، إنّ السّفينة تنتمي لك أنت القبطان
So fight me for her...
...لذلك قاتلني
Monkey D. Luffy!
يا مونكي دي لوفي
I challenge you to a duel!
خض نزالًا معي
What? What? H-Hey... What're you saying?!
ماذا؟ ماذا؟ مهلًا... ماذا تقول؟
At ten o'clock tonight, I'll come back here.
سأعود إلى هنا عند العاشرة من هذه اللّيلة
Then we'll have a duel for the Merry!
ثمّ سنخوض نزالًا من أجل ميري
I'll defeat you and take her!
سأهزمك وآخذ ميري
And then...
...تلك
there'll be nothing left to bind us.
هي نهاية الرّابط بيني وبينكم